## **Ethan Lindsey**

(515)-619-8081 | ethandev.net | ethan.james.lindsey@gmail.com | LinkedIn: ejlindseycs | GitHub: EthanJLindsey

Summary

Recent university graduate with aptitude for detailed analysis and logical reasoning. Strengths in math and computer theory proven by experience tutoring university students. Excels at roles in mathematical or scientific fields especially involved with computer programming. Interested in working with data analytics and software development.

Education

B.S. in Computer Science; Minor in Music Technology

Iowa State University - GPA: 3.91

Experience

**Computer Science Tutor** 

January 2022-December 2022

Iowa State University, Communications Building

Ames, IA

- Tutored 100+ clients on advanced programming practices and concepts.
- Collaborated with team of 10+ tutors to find solutions for complex problems.
- Presented debugging processes on 500+ errors with ~95% success rate.
- Applied solid understanding of third and fourth-year level concepts.

**Student Worker** 

August 2021-December 2021

Iowa State University, Exam Accommodations Center

Ames, IA

- Proctored 100+ students while supplying personalized accommodations.
- Regularly evaluated sensitive confidential information discretely with integrity.
- Addressed diverse critical issues with personalized solutions.

**Projects** 

**Portfolio Website** *July 2023* 

- React website application hosted on and managed using AWS Amplify.
- Wrote 3916 lines of code in JavaScript and CSS total.
- Stores messages from the contact page using CRUM operations and GraphQL API.

August 2022-December 2022 Awards

- Senior design team project created using Flutter and Firebase.
- Contributed ~60% of the code including authentication, profile, and dashboard.
- Improved performance and security by reviewing team contributions daily.
- Weekly sprints following Agile method using Jira.

**Web Adventure** 

- 2D Web-based game made using JavaScript, Kotlin, Spring Boot, and MySQL.
- Used encapsulation and abstraction to decrease development time by ~50%
- User authentication using Spring Security and password encryption.

Technical Skills

Languages

Proficient

C/C++, Java, JavaScript, Dart, Python, MySQL

**Familiar** 

Kotlin, PHP, C#

December 2022 Technologies

AWS, React, NumPy, Spring Boot, Firebase, Flutter,

Node.js

Software

Excel, Docker, Android

Studio

Soft Skills

Critical Analysis **Conflict Resolution Active Learning** 

Adaptability

Relevant Topics

Algorithm Design **Data Structures** 

**Computational Geometry** 

**Network Protocols Network Security** 

ISU Dean's List

December 2019-December 2022

**Highest 2% LAS Freshman** 

July 2022 May 2020

**Highest 2% LAS Junior** 

May 2021